Pushkal Singh (1) Featured

Developer & Trainer seeking assignments in Software Development. Aplication Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Performance Tuning, Solution Architecture, C, C++, VBA, PHP, HTML, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap



Current Location: Dehradun Total Experience: 11 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Dehradun Highest Degree: M.Tech [Thermal Energy and

Environmental Engineering] Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer & Trainer, Software Development, Aplication Programming, Program Management, Project

Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Performance Tuning, Solution Architecture, C, C++, VBA, PHP, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Software Engineering

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

PHP Developer (Jun'19 to Dec'20): About 1 year 6 month of experience as a developer & trainer in Inside Softwares Private Ltd. Assistant Professor Mechanical Engineering (Apr'18 to Jul'18): About 4 months of teaching experience in Dev Bhoomi Institute of Technology(DBIT).

Senior Associate (Oct'11 to Jun'17): About 5 years and 8 months of experience in project KPI dashboard, data management, VBA programming, monitoring and timesheet management as primary tasks in Nagarro Software Private Ltd.

Assistant Manager (Jun' 07 to Jan' 11): About 3 years and 8 months of experience in Chartering of ships with including contract management, KPIs/SLA reporting/monitoring, chartering, customer interface and negotiations in TMILL.

Integrated dual degree (B.Tech + M.Tech) with Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering and Master of Technology specialization in Thermal, Energy and Environmental Engineering from IIT Kharagpur.

Work Experience

Inside Softwares Pvt Ltd as Developer & Trainer-PHP

Jun 2019 to Dec 2020

PHP Core experience: Worked on various Web development projects in PHP language and MYSQL database. Projects include: : https://www.muzicart.com/, https://www.iuu.ac/, https://greenlifebazar.in/,https://bcodr.com/ Proficient in writing MySQL queries to access database and display content dynamically on Web page using core PHP

Assisted Program Manager in conducting training of MS Project to team of executives in Tirupati Medicare, Paonta Sahib, Himachal Pradesh

Created a course from syllabus to content for ISPL Academy on VBA Application Development

Used Power BI Desktop for creating Dashboard for clients.

Knowledge of Laravel but have not build any live website in it.

Dev Bhoomi Institute of Technology as Assistant Professor, Mechanical Engineering Apr 2018 to Jul 2018

Teaching & Presentation Experience: Taught UCMP (Unconventional Manufacturing Processes) and IC Engine subjects as per UTU (Uttarakhand Technical University) syllabus for Bachelor of Technology students. Supervision experience: Supervised labs of 1st Year BTech students in subject BME (Basic Mechanical Engineering).

Nagarro Software Private Ltd as Senior Associate

Oct 2011 to Jun 2017

Data management: Coordinated and conducted data management, data upload, and maintenance of data repository as well as automation of data loading process using VBA(Visual Basic for Application) for excel.

VBA & Macros: Good understanding of excel Macros, VBA programming in excel. Can write modules and VBA scripts of excel to load data in specified excel template.

KPI Dashboard Project: Team member and data analyst for KPI dashboard project of clients Estee Lauder on Qlikview. Data Handled: Handled about 3000 data loads from agreed 45 KPI data files formats into the dashboard on a monthly basis using VBA application and verification using excel functions.

Monitoring: Getting all timesheet filled for about 20 running projects of Lutron client with about 120 resources.

Loading the timesheets data monthly from timesheets to resource and project management tool OpenAirl with applied billing rates for various resources for generating baseline reports and financial reports

Assisted Admin in vendor management of CCTV Cameras and physical security measures.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Mechanical) from Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Kharagpur in 2006

PG: M.Tech (Thermal Energy and Environmental Engineering) from Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Kharagpur in 2007

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
MS word Excel Powerpoint		2008	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Outlook MS Project		2001	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
C, Power BI		2007	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
C ++ VBA		2005	4 Month(s)	
Php HTML5		2005	4 Month(s)	
css3 JQuery		2005	4 Month(s)	
BOOTSTRAP		2007	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

US Work Status: Authorized to Work in the US

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time